But again, welcome everybody for Abra
for GitHub office hours call. Uh let's
head over to the agenda. There's
actually not not much to cover
today. Um so we did ship version
7.0 and that included the support for
deploying to sandbox environments from a
pool request that was previously in
preview and also the new page scripting
visualizer
uh in preview. Right now we I think have
a bunch of u fixes. So we kind of in the
last month we focused on um making like
the the version uh stronger and better.
I think soon we will release version 7.1
so you can get these um the fixes uh
released officially. We again prepared a
demo repo where you can like pretty much
like see what's what the new thing is.
But in this case it's actually only the
page scripting visualizer. And here I
just included a screenshot for from this
repo. This is a screenshot from a CI/CD
run. And base scripting on its own it's
not new. It's only the visualizing part
that it's new. Uh here you can see like
the failing, passing tests, skip test
and as well as like the overall time
that the test took to run. Uh this is
just for convenience. Uh if you're used
to looking into like these uh summaries
um we are also taking this forum as uh
an opportunity to make an announcement.
Indeed, all BC container helper versions
before version 6.1 might not work after
May 1st. At least like major
functionalities will be broken. Um this
is due to some security related work
that uh we we needed to do. Uh this is a
link to the ping issue on on container
helper repository where you can read a
little bit more. And uh it's worth
noting that repositories that run any
version of a go for GitHub will not be
affected. Uh with that I think we are
ready to start the Q&A or open
discussion depending if you have
questions or feedback bring them up now.
Sebastian Shu asks or says not about the
topics today but can you please share
infos about the progress of front
package integration feature in AO go? Uh
Freddy this one take that one. Um so it
is one of the two big topics that that
we're going to work on I'm going to work
on at least in this release over the
next months.
um where right now it's the
customization pieces and this one is
after that. So runtime package
generation or integration I'm I'm
thinking generation because integration
is already kind of of up to date but the
entire Nougat story should be finalized
before October 1st is the goal and have
something that works well in algo. The
the issue that we've been waiting for
was the modern dev team to create a
compiler that could generate runtime
packages without us having to spin up a
container. I have not received
confirmation for that. So, we'll go
ahead and create something that works
without it and then uh we'll optimize it
if we ever get the optimized version of
that to save some runner time.
Really hope that's answers the question.
But yeah, if you want a date, uh,
October 1st is the best date, but it's
probably going to be before that.
We have a question from Florian. Florian
Rock asks, "Is there a way to pass
parameters to BC container helper when
using local dev PS1? I tried setting
default new container parameters in the
local event settings JSON. Let me
actually see it's more but it doesn't
seem to
work this case. Yeah, specifically I
need to use use
SSL from local dev. Um as far as I know
um
probably not. I mean this is something
we need to look at I think
because so I don't think it's possible
to do that to to do that today. No no
yeah
is use SSL as an um a parameter in newb
container. Yes. So you can have a you
can add a script override maybe for newb
container. Uh the local dev would that
work in local de that would work I
think that yeah that would work um
okay so it's a bit cumbersome but but
yes like that will
work you can explain it.
Yes. So essentially when you call uh
local dev uh when when so we'll by
behind the scenes we're going to call
runo pipeline nf container helper and
runo pipeline when it creates the new
container it'll look for a script with a
specific name and then if you add that
script you can override the
functionality of the new BC container so
that you can add parameter and I can
I'll try to link some documentation and
we actually do this in the BC apps repo
as well so I can I can link an example
of how we do that there so you can
see. But that's I guess it's the only
way right now.
Oh, so Florian uh continues with it is
possible to pass enable
taskuler in the setting though, which is
strange.
Um do
you
So is there maybe a setting we don't
transfer?
might be that we if we if we actually
pass the settings to local dev maybe use
SSO is not one of the settings we we
transfer I don't know actually to be
honest we need to investigate Florian
it's not something at least on top of my
mind
enable task is a setting specifically
enable though but use SSL or like yeah
but there are like settings that are
transferred to there like ago settings
that are transferred to I think he if he
sets that set that is default
new container parameter like there's a
setting in BC container elbow that's
called default new container parameters
um and there if he sets the the enable
task scheduleuler then it works uh but
if if he sets the the use it doesn't um
but yeah the override will definitely
work. If you want a better solution than
that, Floren, you can create a
discussion on on ALGO and we can try to
find a solution there that we can maybe
is a little smarter that you can use.
But
um probably yeah, find a
way. We have a couple of more questions
coming in. Sebastian asks any known
issues about PC27 and code signing.
There's something changed regarded to
the generated app files
BC27. So that's that's the insider
version. I don't
not aware. Not aware. Yeah. Is there
like particular scenario that is broken?
or
it' be good to hear if you're facing
issues with it because then you might
not be the only one.
Let's uh see maybe we're going to
hear a further comment on this one.
Then Eric Van, I'm sorry I cannot read
your name. We are using AO go with great
success for outsource apps but it's
lacking any options for building runtime
files for old BC majors on prem any
plans for adding support for that for
example using preprocessor directives
that would be a massive help for ISVS we
are forced uh we are forced to use
custom scripts now
um yeah short answer to that is no but
maybe we
can consider But I don't know, Freddy,
you being the Yeah, today we don't have
the runtime generation yet, but I don't
I don't see any reason when we add that
uh that that we shouldn't support this.
And and with the with the latest edition
in the last version where you can now do
build modes and you can do pre-processor
symbols in build modes, you could
actually build your app for app source
and on prem in two different build modes
and then generate uh runtime packages
for for for for both as well. Um,
so it's it's like together with the the
Nougat thing, uh, generating Nougat
packages with runtime packages is
probably the direction we're going to go
in algo and then you'll just have to
figure out how to grab these nougats and
and install them on on premises. It's
just a zip file. You can unpack it. So,
um, but that's that's the storage
mechanism we're going to use in in algo.
And I I don't see a reason why why that
didn't just work.
Okay, I hope the question was somewhat
answered. Now going back to Sebastian
Shu's question about
um not working properly on VC27. He says
the app file seems not to be in valid
format. Next major validation stopped
working since Sunday. I investigate and
bring more info to this. Um if you
believe that this is something that we
broke like B business central team broke
please create an issue on a go I would
imagine go repository we need to
investigate this if it's general issue
please remember to also include how you
do the signing. Are you using uh managed
signing? Are you using a pfx file? by
using
um yeah which how legacy signing managed
signing or Azure trusted signing.
Yeah, thank you for that clarification
Freddy. Now to Florianki question. Would
it be possible to make announcements
like the one for
V6.1 more prominent instead of only
posting them in a GitHub issue? Maybe in
the future a notice could be shown
directly when running a command in
PowerShell might not be easy but still
wanted to suggest it. Uh this is I
believe related to
the kind of like the announcement about
BC container
helper. Uh we can um we can definitely
think about
it if if that's going to help.
Oh, the the problem is if you have an
old version, how do we know in the old
version that it's not going to work at a
specific date? It's a probably hard. Um
I think we've always said when you're
using container ala, you always need to
be in the latest version. If something
doesn't work, try to upgrade and then if
it doesn't work, file an issue. And and
that's still how it's going to be be. Um
I think we also posted something in
various locations uh on the same topic.
So yeah, not sure we can do much more.
We we'll make sure that people using
algo never sees these things. It's it's
really not relevant for anybody on this
call. But if people are using con for
something uh themselves, then yeah, that
might be necessary to upgrade.
Uh, okay. Now, off to the chat again. Uh
I mean please don't use the chat for
questions but uh let's let's take this
one as well by
uh
Steve Christristianos sorry if I
mispronounce your name not an go
question but relevant with busy
container helper slated for retirement
in the next two three years we with will
with its powershell gallery successor
have any gaps in terms of functionality
for spinning up type onre and type
sandbox vic containers on a VM.
We use this quite a bit to spin up
containers. One BC BC container per
developer version country with the
use use traffic option for developers to
uh unit testing their branches. Um
yeah, so
um there's definitely going to be some
gaps in the functionality. We're not
going to just take new BC container and
move it as is. Uh we are going to
support both onrem and sandbox
containers. I I don't see how we can get
around that. Uh the use traffic is
something we'll need to like have a look
at if if we can create it in a way so
that these things could be added on
instead of built in because use traffic
has given us a lot of support issues
over the times. So, so if if we can make
the new command in a way so that these
things could be added in a in a separate
like partner uh partner driven open
source module or something like that.
That would be my preferred option on
that. Um every every time there's
problems with traffic, I spend hours and
hours on that. uh and and it's just
horrible to to get back to those things
because we don't need it. We don't use
it at all. So So these things would be
better off uh like on the side than
inside. I hope
that's understandable.
But the idea on the container helper
deprecation is really that we'll take
all the things that we need for DevOps
and put those into modules inside of
ALGO. So the shipping vehicle for those
modules would be algo. We're not going
to publish those modules on on the
PowerShell gallery. We're going to
create a
PowerShell module in the gallery that
kind of takes care of the onrem or the
things that you want to run locally uh
which is not the building and not the
publishing to to online environments and
all of these things those are DevOps
tasks but all the tasks that you
typically run locally uh those would be
available there. So maybe five commands
or 10 commands I don't know we haven't
like gotten to that point yet. Um but
but those things will be available and
and uh I'll probably reach out and get
some partners input on what they use and
how they use it locally. Uh and then see
what we can get around when we when we
get closer to those things.
Yeah. So in short there will be like the
new version of BC container helper will
be way slimmer and uh we'll focus on
functionality for local development for
it. The rest will be part of a goal.
Okay. Any more
questions? There hasn't been anything
new last five, six
minutes.
Um, you have anybody from Spain or
Portugal on the call? Do you have power
down there?
Okay. So, Florian uh Roka says,
"Regarding the deprecation of BC
container helper, the bottom line would
be that it would be again truly um basic
container helper. So, no worries at all.
Yes, in a way, yes, there will be like
functionality supporting uh work with
containers. It's just that the current
module grew up so much that it's kind of
it um it just gathers a lot of uh
functionality that it's not necessarily
even related to containers. For
instance, like there is a lot of
functionality that is a go specific
nowadays. So we're trying to decouple
those by um uh by depregating the old
module but there will be like a new
solution. So it's not like we are like
hanging out to dry. We're just like the
announcement of the retiring of basic
container helper doesn't mean that
there's not going to be uh some um some
other solution. It's just that we
haven't do it yet.
The announcement is really mostly for
people who are using their own self-made
DevOps solution because they'll have a
lot of work to do when these things
split up and these things are coming in
different modules with different
parameter sets and all of these things.
So, so our recommendation is instead of
waiting two years now and then having a
lot of coding in front of them, spend
some time now to ship to a managed
DevOps solution and then you don't have
to ever worry about those things again.
That's the reason why this message comes
two years in advance. Um, and not not
because people need to start recoding
now. Uh, if people want to code
themselves,
uh, they need to wait until there's
something uh that they can use. But we
we recommend not to do things
themselves. So, Jose Martinez is from
Spain. So, you have power on there.
That's great. Good to hear.
There's still quite a lot of people
online. So, please join the discussion,
ask your questions or share feedback
should you have any. It's this is kind
of the forum to do it. This is where you
get to talk with us or at least you
write to us and we talk to you.
Maybe we can uh maybe we can share a few
things on how we've split things up with
issues and discussions and and the
project plan. Uh do you want to do that
Maria
to share the well? Sorry, I'm a bit
brain dead today, but I can uh I just
talk about like what issues are for and
what discussions are for and so yeah, we
can let's let's do that. Yes, share the
algo homepage and then just have a quick
let's actually see to have it pinned
here.
Uh so actually I think was it last month
we announced that we're going to start
using discussions. The um GitHub feature
has GitHub has this feature called
discussions where you get to kind of um
ask questions or like uh suggest ideas
and you get to vote and we get to engage
in different
conversations. Uh there has been like
some quite good activity. It's like very
healthy. We want to like as many um
people to to join whether you are an
experienced a go for GitHub user or like
an early adopter it's all fine we
welcome everybody
uh and then um I think the the idea was
that uh previously we used issues where
you could kind of like create different
issues based on whether you want to
whether you want a qu whether you have a
question or whether you wanted to
suggest um an an idea but uh with issue
there's like some limitations and then
on top of that actual issues were a bit
bur uh down so I think going forward
with using discussions it's a better
approach uh and then on top of that we
want to grow like a healthy community
around a go where uh it's not only us
who could answer questions so in case
we're not available then maybe there
there's someone else who can who can um
like help you out. Um I don't know what
else it's um the idea also is that
uh I'm not sure if we are like if what
I'm going to say is what we're going to
do because Freddy please keep me honest
but we have the ideas tab here that you
can see and um in certain periods we're
going to get the top most voted ideas.
We don't have like a set count but
something that we're going to actually
focus on implementing. So this is your
way of driving the development of a go
for GitHub. So exactly. So the ideas in
here, you guys can can help like vote up
ideas that you think are great and we'll
have a look at that and we if we can see
ideas that are are like having a lot of
votes, they they'll they're going to be
more likely to be implemented. It's not
like we we can promise anything, but
stuff like the NG get thing is
definitely something we're working on.
code coverage is also something that
that we we I hope we'll be be able to do
but but the other things please vote up
on things. We'll move the things from
this one to the backlog in the project
plan and then we'll implement it from
there. Right now there's an ideas list
in the project plan as well and we're
going to move those back to discussions
like we moved a lot of bugs and
enhancements from from issues to
discussions. And if if we find things in
ideas to be categorized as a bug or a
question to be categorized as a bug,
we're going to we're going to move it to
issues and then fix it as a bug or move
it to the project ban and fix it as a as
a as a work item or as a as a yeah
enhancement. uh really so discussions is
kind of where discussions start and
enhancements get gets like baked and
then move them to to either box or or
project is kind of the idea. Let's hope
that we can manage that. Yeah. And uh
when you actually create new new idea
for instance, make sure like it hasn't
been covered already. Uh just scan use
the search or something. It's uh not
good to have duplicates
and yeah let's see if we have questions
that like the chat has
been no questions nothing in the
chat but still people are online
so we have very a handful of active
users today but yeah okay okay Steve uh
asks I have another rookie question
branch strategies and their best
practices. Currently, we avoid merging
untested code into the main branch of
our aogo repos and instead create
alternate main star branches. For
example, to target the next BC major and
or monthly features and fixes to our
product. We call those branches epics in
the jur world. Once everything's been
tested, I PR merge that community branch
into main. Is that a sound approach or
am I off or am I off my
rocker? Okay. Uh I think that's pretty
pretty good approach. I mean depends it
really depends on like
uh like the developers like how many
developers work on particular feature
and uh like your also your release
strategy could affect the way you
branch. So uh there is no right or wrong
solution when it comes to uh branching.
I think uh uh Freddy uh suggested has
some branching strategy suggested in
uh presentations related
to a go I would imagine
I think it's go somewhere
in I'll I'll find the docs but yeah
but again
uh like if it works for you that's fine
I mean it's branching strategies like
change all the time. But if it works for
you, if you feel that that way you
manage to ship a stable code and you
manage to kind of quickly revert if
something uh goes off, that's that I
think that these are good signs that
it's working for
you. Uh and again like there are no I
mean it's not like necessarily related
to a goal but it's uh any question is
welcome. anything we you think we can
help
with. We are halfway through
uh today's office hours
call. We got uh already several
questions. Uh but we still
have people online. So if you want to
share something, it's also fine to
listen. You know
that's maybe you just uh like us talking
uh anything else pretty or any of uh the
rest Alex or Spassin if you want to
share something about uh discussions or
let me be the project board
here. Yeah.
Yes. So on the branching strategy, one
of the things I like to do and I
actually learned that from Maria is to
open a pull request early because that
way I can easily I can easily take the
changes to main and merge back into my
my development branch. Um, and if I
don't do that, it tends to become like a
huge merge process when you want to
merge your branch back into main. So
having a a pull request open and
updating it like regularly allows you to
have multiple branches that can be like
developing side by side and and
integrate those later.
Oh, there it is.
Okay, no more questions. Yeah, I think
um
round up to 5:35. If no one uh asks the
questions until then, I think we can
uh give ourselves some some time back.
Okay. Okay. Someone spray enough.
Sebastian show.
says asks it is a bit off topic but do
you know a way to prevent behinds in a
pull request in Azure DevOps I think in
GitHub there is a setting for this uh in
Azure DevOps I haven't seen anything um
that that is the same I think on GitHub
there is this maybe I can try and see if
we have some of the old pull
requests
Um, no, even this one is up to date. Oh,
wow. Okay, this one. Yeah, that one is
probably not.
Yes. So, on GitHub, I think what also
Freddy was referring to a little bit
ago. Um you can set up this way. You can
kind of like require branches to be up
to date and this like this action would
appear on the pull request and this
update branch will pretty much like pull
the target branch into the the PR branch
like all commits uh will be will be done
um in conflicts they'll be you you solve
them right here. Yeah, that that as
well. Azure DevOps. Alex, do you know
anything that uh but maybe I'm wrong.
Pardon? Maybe I'm wrong. I don't recall
seeing such a feature. Yeah, just
another reason to move to GitHub, right?
Yeah, good point. Good
point. Um so sorry we Yeah, I mean we
don't I haven't seen it and you know we
do also support some repositories in
Azure DevOps. So, it's uh it hasn't been
a thing that's been brought
up. That was indeed a bit off topic.
Still happy to help if we if we could
actually see we have a comment in this
one. Yeah. Yeah. We couldn't really help
you, but you're
welcome. I think the numbers of
attendees is slowly dropping. I guess um
people either heard what they came to
hear
um or they don't have questions. Again,
maybe just a couple more minutes if
someone again wants to ask something. As
you see, we're happy to help with
anything related to development in this
case. But please try to focus on a go or
VC container
helper. It's uh this is the forum and
The rest you can use copilot for some
assistance as well. I think they could
copilot can do a better job in answering
some of these questions to be honest.
We should have copilot listening into
these office hours. And answering
questions. Yeah.
Okay. I think we should say uh thanks
for joining us and uh if there are any
more questions or topics that you want
to discuss then then the discussions on
Microsoft go uh would be a good place to
start them and we'll answer
there. Thanks for driving this Maria.
Yeah, thank you for answering most of
the questions and thank everybody who
joined and shared their questions and
feedback and thoughts.
Uh we're looking forward to next month
where the office hour will be a morning
one. I think that's what we agreed on.
Yep. I don't know the exact dates but
there will be an announcement.
Last Tuesday of the month.
Last
Tuesday May
whenever. Okay. Thank you everybody and
see you. Bye bye.